<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://julesstuart.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://julesstuart.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-05-04T01:35:28+00:00</updated><id>https://julesstuart.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jules Stuart</title><subtitle>The personal webpage of Jules M. Stuart. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">about the furby</title><link href="https://julesstuart.com/blog/2025/about-the-furby/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="about the furby"/><published>2025-05-03T21:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-03T21:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://julesstuart.com/blog/2025/about-the-furby</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://julesstuart.com/blog/2025/about-the-furby/"><![CDATA[<p>I never had an original Furby when I was a kid. But, boy, do I remember them. Who doesn’t?</p> <p>In retrospect, I have always been intrigued by the Furby. It is a simple hardware I/O device made to behave in a cute and engaging way. Its purpose is to be fun to play with. Pure form over function.</p> <p>It is a technologically-advanced item that doesn’t actually <em>do</em> anything. And I think that it’s a bold artistic statement.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="ramblings"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[what could go wrong?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">hello, world</title><link href="https://julesstuart.com/blog/2023/hello-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="hello, world"/><published>2023-03-25T21:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-25T21:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://julesstuart.com/blog/2023/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://julesstuart.com/blog/2023/hello-world/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello. If you’re reading this, then I guess it means that I finally made the website. Glad to finally cross that off the list, personally.</p> <p>So, uh, what’s gonna go here? Well, I’ve got a few near-term ideas, but mostly, I just want to see where things go after I get in the swing of maintaining the blog. I think it’s safe to say you can expect a lot of electronics and software projects. You’ll find some passionate nerd-posting about video games, music and movies. There will almost certainly be some attempts to teach quantum physics. And if you stay around long enough, then things may even get philosophical.</p> <p>Tonight, I’m hacking away on this website, and I’m listening to YouTube’s AI-generated, personalized music video playlist. The sun’s going down later, but it’s still quite cold. In that very early phase of Spring when it feels like the year has just shown itself for what it will be.</p> <p>There’s a sense of promise in the air. I stare out the window, and I have a few good ideas that I feel like I should probably write down.</p> <p>-Jules</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="ramblings"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[testing, testing...one, two, three]]></summary></entry></feed>