<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://julesstuart.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://julesstuart.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-05-14T01:16:56+00:00</updated><id>https://julesstuart.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jules Stuart</title><subtitle>The personal webpage of Jules M. Stuart. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">visit to boston</title><link href="https://julesstuart.com/blog/2025/visit-to-boston/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="visit to boston"/><published>2025-05-12T22:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-12T22:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://julesstuart.com/blog/2025/visit-to-boston</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://julesstuart.com/blog/2025/visit-to-boston/"><![CDATA[<div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0" style="margin:auto;width:500px"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/boston_050825-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/boston_050825-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/boston_050825-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/boston_050825.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <p><br/></p> <p>I spent a long weekend in Boston recently, staying in Back Bay—an area I was eager to revisit, having lived there back in 2016. As with everywhere I visited, not much had changed, but if you looked long enough, you could spot the differences. A shop or two might be different. Or the odd building that I definitely didn’t recognize.</p> <p>While I was there, I visited the MIT Museum, which I had never been to before. It recently relocated to Kendall Square, which is looking very sleek and modern–no longer the construction site I remember from my time there. The museum is impressive, and they have a wide variety of exhibits describing some of MIT’s contributions to various fields. I sat for a bit in a room with artistic depictions of some possible outcomes of <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2019/08/09/615/what-is-geoengineering-and-why-should-you-care-climate-change-harvard/">geoengineering</a>, feeling that odd mix of excitement and dread one feels when pondering too long on that cyberpunk future. I saw some backup components of the original Apollo Guidance Computer and admired an impressive collection of gadgets from throughout the last century.</p> <p>One particularly interesting thing for me was a display dedicated to <a href="https://www.lego.com/en-us/themes/mindstorms/about">Lego Mindstorms</a>. I will always remember the Mindstorms set very fondly–it was the original gateway for me into a career in technology. The set was my introduction to programming and engineering concepts like sensing and feedback. I can trace a clear through line from that point to high school lab experiments to graduate research to now.</p> <p>One of the key figures in early development of Mindstorms was the MIT professor <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seymour_Papert">Seymour Papert</a>, who wanted to use Lego as a way of enabling children to make machines that ran with the Logo programming language that he had developed. Papert was an advocate of an educational theory known as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constructionism_(learning_theory)">Constructionism</a>. This theory emphasizes the importance of learning through guided discovery, using what one has already learned in order to build new knowledge. Papert captured these ideas in a book titled <em>Mindstorms: Children, Computers, and Powerful Ideas</em> (available <a href="https://dl.acm.org/doi/book/10.5555/1095592">online</a> via ACM Digital Library), which is where the Lego product got its name.</p> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0" style="margin:auto"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0" style="margin:auto;width:500px"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/sitz_mindstorms-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/sitz_mindstorms-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/sitz_mindstorms-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/sitz_mindstorms.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <center>Mindstorms contraption for rotating an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Acousto-optic_modulator">AOM</a> created for a senior lab project at UT, c. 2013</center> </div> <p><br/></p> <p>I’ve always thought of Lego, and especially Mindstorms, as one of the key pieces in my approach to learning. I’m a tactile learner; I don’t ever understand as well as I do when I can feel how something works. Lego always appealed to me for this hands-on element, but it also fascinated me with its presentation of process. The instructions lay out precisely where, what, and how much to add, step-by-step, allowing you to methodically create the end result. Seeing the way that motors, sensors, and programmatic control could be added to these creations, I could understand the method by which even more complicated things were created. Even when I didn’t understand the technology around me, I understood the process. The key was to learn to build pieces of the big and impossible thing. Build enough pieces, and you eventually grasp the whole thing.</p> <p>And it occurs to me, as I’m researching the history of Mindstorms and the educational philosophy behind it: this was the plan all along. I was one of the beneficiaries of that new wave of teaching that came about in the 80’s. It seems to me that it has come full circle in a way. Not only has this influence helped make me into a scientist, it has made me realize the importance of this style of teaching and learning. I realize that I’m a member of the Mindstorms generation. Not just a learner, but a builder and a tinkerer; dedicated to showing others how to do the same.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="ramblings"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[it happened on newbury street]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">about the furby</title><link href="https://julesstuart.com/blog/2025/about-the-furby/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="about the furby"/><published>2025-05-03T21:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-03T21:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://julesstuart.com/blog/2025/about-the-furby</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://julesstuart.com/blog/2025/about-the-furby/"><![CDATA[<div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0" style="margin:auto;width:500px"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/furby-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/furby-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/furby-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/furby.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <p>I never had an original Furby when I was a kid. But, boy, do I remember them. Who doesn’t?</p> <p>It sticks out in my mind as one of those things that was at first very mysterious but became deeply familiar over time. At its core, the Furby is a collection of simple I/O peripherals orchestrated by a microcontroller. It’s the kind of thing that shows up in my work in the lab all the time, so I know it well. Yet the Furby is fundamentally different from my usual instruments because it is a technologically-advanced item that doesn’t actually <em>do</em> anything. And I think that makes it a bold artistic statement.</p> <p>At one point in my life, it was an unknown entity–something which might have been capable of learning new tricks or performing creepy acts of sentience. I can clearly remember rumors about Furbies waking up, chattering in the middle of the night. They will always be a bit of an urban legend, and they just so happen to be the exact kind of thing that I like to tinker with these days.</p> <p>So I bought a Furby with the intention of giving it a little “tweak” to make it an entry for a Halloween contest. Some might say that it’s creepy enough as-is, but I’ve always been a big believer in pushing the limits of spookiness. I’m channeling my inner Frankenstein here. I need to replace the brain.</p> <p>The goal is to clone a Raspberry Pi Pico to replace the Furby’s microcontroller. With programmatic control over the Furby’s inputs and outputs, an interesting world of possibilities opens up. The art of the hack will be its subtlety. From the outside, it should not be possible to detect any change to the Furby. But something about it will be just a little different from how you remember. Were they always this…strange?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="ramblings"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[what could go wrong?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">hello, world</title><link href="https://julesstuart.com/blog/2023/hello-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="hello, world"/><published>2023-03-25T21:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-25T21:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://julesstuart.com/blog/2023/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://julesstuart.com/blog/2023/hello-world/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello. If you’re reading this, then I guess it means that I finally made the website. Glad to finally cross that off the list, personally.</p> <p>So, uh, what’s gonna go here? Well, I’ve got a few near-term ideas, but mostly, I just want to see where things go after I get in the swing of maintaining the blog. I think it’s safe to say you can expect a lot of electronics and software projects. You’ll find some passionate nerd-posting about video games, music and movies. There will almost certainly be some attempts to teach quantum physics. And if you stay around long enough, then things may even get philosophical.</p> <p>Tonight, I’m hacking away on this website, and I’m listening to YouTube’s AI-generated, personalized music video playlist. The sun’s going down later, but it’s still quite cold. In that very early phase of Spring when it feels like the year has just shown itself for what it will be.</p> <p>There’s a sense of promise in the air. I stare out the window, and I have a few good ideas that I feel like I should probably write down.</p> <p>-Jules</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="ramblings"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[testing, testing...one, two, three]]></summary></entry></feed>