<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://julesstuart.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://julesstuart.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-05-04T20:18:29+00:00</updated><id>https://julesstuart.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jules Stuart</title><subtitle>The personal webpage of Jules M. Stuart. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">about the furby</title><link href="https://julesstuart.com/blog/2025/about-the-furby/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="about the furby"/><published>2025-05-03T21:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-03T21:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://julesstuart.com/blog/2025/about-the-furby</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://julesstuart.com/blog/2025/about-the-furby/"><![CDATA[<div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0" style="margin:auto;width:500px"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/furby-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/furby-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/furby-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/furby.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <p>I never had an original Furby when I was a kid. But, boy, do I remember them. Who doesn’t?</p> <p>It sticks out in my mind as one of those things that was at first very mysterious but became deeply familiar over time. At its core, the Furby is a collection of simple I/O peripherals orchestrated by a microcontroller. It’s the kind of thing that shows up in my work in the lab all the time, so I know it well. Yet the Furby is fundamentally different from my usual instruments because it is a technologically-advanced item that doesn’t actually <em>do</em> anything. And I think that makes it a bold artistic statement.</p> <p>At one point in my life, it was an unknown entity–something which might have been capable of learning new tricks or performing creepy acts of sentience. I can clearly remember rumors about Furbies waking up, chattering in the middle of the night. They will always be a bit of an urban legend, and they just so happen to be the exact kind of thing that I like to tinker with these days.</p> <p>So I bought a Furby with the intention of giving it a little “tweak” to make it an entry for a Halloween contest. Some might say that it’s creepy enough as-is, but I’ve always been a big believer in pushing the limits of spookiness. I’m channeling my inner Frankenstein here. I need to replace the brain.</p> <p>The goal is to clone a Raspberry Pi Pico to replace the Furby’s microcontroller. With programmatic control over the Furby’s inputs and outputs, an interesting world of possibilities opens up. The art of the hack will be its subtlety. From the outside, it should not be possible to detect any change to the Furby. But something about it will be just a little different from how you remember. Were they always this…strange?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="ramblings"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[what could go wrong?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">hello, world</title><link href="https://julesstuart.com/blog/2023/hello-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="hello, world"/><published>2023-03-25T21:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-25T21:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://julesstuart.com/blog/2023/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://julesstuart.com/blog/2023/hello-world/"><![CDATA[<p>Hello. If you’re reading this, then I guess it means that I finally made the website. Glad to finally cross that off the list, personally.</p> <p>So, uh, what’s gonna go here? Well, I’ve got a few near-term ideas, but mostly, I just want to see where things go after I get in the swing of maintaining the blog. I think it’s safe to say you can expect a lot of electronics and software projects. You’ll find some passionate nerd-posting about video games, music and movies. There will almost certainly be some attempts to teach quantum physics. And if you stay around long enough, then things may even get philosophical.</p> <p>Tonight, I’m hacking away on this website, and I’m listening to YouTube’s AI-generated, personalized music video playlist. The sun’s going down later, but it’s still quite cold. In that very early phase of Spring when it feels like the year has just shown itself for what it will be.</p> <p>There’s a sense of promise in the air. I stare out the window, and I have a few good ideas that I feel like I should probably write down.</p> <p>-Jules</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="ramblings"/><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[testing, testing...one, two, three]]></summary></entry></feed>